Hello, welcome everybody. How is everybody doing today? This is going to be an
大家好，欢迎各位。大家今天怎么样？这将是一堂
awesome listening and speaking class. I'm so glad that all of you are here. Welcome
非常棒的听说课。我很高兴大家都能来。欢迎
everybody. Like training a muscle. The brain is not a muscle but we build
各位。就像训练肌肉一样。大脑不是肌肉，但我们建立
connections. We build stronger connections and so our aim today is for your
连接。我们建立更强的连接，所以我们今天的目标是让你们的
answers to try to be natural, fluent and clear. You might notice that I'm
回答尽量做到自然、流利和清晰。你们可能注意到我会在你们说话时
typing as you speak. Try to look at some of these corrections that I'm making
打字。请试着看看我做的一些修改，
some of them are just rephrasing of what you could say maybe a little bit
其中一些只是对你们或许可以表达得更好一点的说法进行了调整。
better. It improve your fluency. But I don't want it to interrupt your speaking.
这会提高你们的流利度。但我不想它打断你们的发言。
Just try to focus on being natural, fluent and clear. The whole goal is to
请尽量专注于自然、流利和清晰。总的目标是
understand and be understood. Here's a question. What's one thing you already feel
理解和被理解。这里有一个问题。说英语时，你已经对哪一点
good about when speaking English? I don't know. That's a hard one. Okay, so I
感觉良好？我不知道。这可难倒我了。好的，所以我想
think it's like now when I speak English, I don't feel like embarrassed if
现在我说英语的时候，如果有人纠正我，
something somebody correct me. So I think that's what something I feel good
我不会觉得尴尬。所以我想这是我现在感觉良好的一点。
now. That comes with experience really. That does help. And the next one, what's
这确实是经验积累的结果。这确实有帮助。下一个问题，你认为
one area you think might be challenging in an English interview and why? I think
英语面试中哪个方面可能具有挑战性，为什么？我想
it will be like the new vocabulary and (I) have to express or like as you mentioned
可能是新的词汇，而且我必须表达，或者像您提到的，
trying to put what I'm thinking in something like a more clear and in short.
努力把我正在思考的内容用更清晰、更简短的方式表达出来。
*In size. Yes. Okay. And trying to say something clearly and concisely.
简洁。是的。好的。努力把事情说得清晰而简洁。
All right. I agree. All of these things can be improved too the more you do it. So we
好的。我同意。所有这些事情也都可以通过多做来改进。所以我们
could try to improve how we say things to make them more clear or concise in
可以在今天的课程中尝试改进我们说话的方式，使其更清晰或更简洁。
today's lesson. One of the most popular interview questions that they ask is
他们最常问的面试问题之一是
tell me about yourself. They want you to open up. They want you to break the ice.
“请介绍一下你自己”。他们希望你敞开心扉。他们希望你打破冷场。
They've asked this question a million times. Some people use this in order to
他们问过这个问题无数次了。有些人用这个问题来
impress the other person or like I said, break the ice. What do they really want?
给对方留下深刻印象，或者像我说的，打破冷场。他们真正想要的是什么？
What they really want is something brief, right? One to two minutes. A relevant
他们真正想要的是简短的介绍，对吧？一到两分钟。一个关于你的专业背景、
summary of your professional background, your skills, career goals, these
你的技能、职业目标的有针对性的总结，这些
essential things that they need to know. Why? Because if this is the first question,
他们需要了解的基本信息。为什么？因为如果这是第一个问题，
they need to have a very good one, a very strong positive first impression of
他们需要对你有一个非常好的、非常强烈且积极的第一印象，
you for that first question they ask. Here's an activity for your dream job. What
对于他们问的第一个问题。这里有一个关于你梦想工作的活动。在你的“介绍一下
are one to two key achievements or skills you'd highlight and your tell me about
你自己”的回答中，你会强调哪一到两个关键成就或技能？
yourself answer. What are two skills or achievements you would highlight? I think it
你会强调哪两个技能或成就？我想
will be something related with decision making. And I think the other one will be
会是与决策能力相关的。然后另一个我想会是
with like, I don't know how to say it's like when you learn something by
关于，我不知道怎么说……就是当你自学 (zìxué) 某些东西的时候。
yourself. So one skill is that you are good at making decisions and that you
所以一个技能是你擅长做决定，另一个是
and the other one is that you know a lot about yourself. The other one is like if
你很了解自己。另一个是，如果
I don't if I don't know something, I look for it until I know it. Okay. And I
我不知道某件事，我会一直查找直到我知道为止。好的。而且我
learn, I try to learn by myself before I on your own. Right, so learn on my
会尝试自己学习，在我……靠自己。是的，所以在寻求帮助之前，我会自己学习。
own before I asked for help. So you consider yourself to be an autonomous
靠自己学习。所以你认为自己是一个有自主性的人。
person. You're capable of working alone autonomously. Is that right? Yes, I can
你能够独立自主地工作。是这样吗？是的，我
work both, but yeah, I try to look first by myself. And I think this would
两者都可以，但是，是的，我会先尝试自己解决。而且我认为这会
highlight the fact that you are capable of making good decisions that they're
突出你能够做出正确决定的能力，他们将不必对你的工作
not going to have to micromanage what you do that you trust that you can find
事无巨细地管理，他们相信你能找到正确的答案，
the correct answer that you're not going to be a burden on them and that you
你不会成为他们的负担，并且你拥有必要的技能。我认为这是给人留下
have the necessary skills. I think that's a good way to make a good first
良好第一印象的好方法。
impression. Yeah, yes. So we have some different phrases that we can use to answer
嗯，是的。所以我们有一些不同的短语可以用来回答这个问题。
this question. For example, if I were to tell someone about myself, I'd say my
例如，如果我要向别人介绍我自己，我会说我的名字是戴维·布朗。
name is David Brown. I'm passionate about teaching English as a second
我对作为第二语言的英语教学充满热情。
language. I've had about 24,000 sessions online with students from all around
我与来自世界各地的学生进行了大约24000次在线课程。
the world. I have taught younger students in middle school and high school
我教过初中和高中的年轻学生，
really identify with the work that I do in my free time. I think about it as
我对我所做的工作有很强的认同感。在我的空闲时间，我也会思考它。
well. I like to spend time with my family and friends and dream about new
我喜欢和家人朋友共度时光，并梦想着新的
technology. I don't know. That's what I might have a job interview in a
技术。我不知道。如果我稍后有一个工作面试，我可能会这么说。
little bit. Norma, tell me, do you think that would make a good first impression?
诺玛 (Nuòmǎ)，告诉我，你认为这会给人留下一个好的第一印象吗？
Yes. Oh, I hope so. I don't know if this lesson is better for me or for you
是的。哦，我希望如此。我不知道这节课对我更好还是对你更好，
actually. Thank you. Thank you. Norma, this lesson is free. All right, so what made
说实话。谢谢你。谢谢。诺玛，这节课是免费的。好了，那么是什么让
that example easy to understand? I think I spoke a little bit too fast, but what
那个例子容易理解呢？我想我可能说得有点太快了，但是你
do you think? What made that example easy to understand? No, actually, what I
怎么看？是什么让那个例子容易理解？不，实际上，我
like listen (heard) was about the time that you have the experience that you have.
听到的是关于您所拥有的经验。
And also I can see like with the range of age that you can work. So
而且我还能看出您可以胜任的年龄段范围。所以
I know that you can do it with older or younger. And also that you are somebody
我知道您可以和年长或年轻的人一起工作。而且您还是一个
that takes care of our family. Okay, also, yeah, you have some good listening
照顾家庭的人。好的，另外，是的，你已经具备了很好的听力技巧。
skills already. What I, instead of saying what I listen*, you could say what I, what
我，与其说“我听到的*”，你可以说“我，我听说的”，
I heard rather, you could say what I heard was about the experience that you
更确切地说，你可以说“我听到的是关于你所拥有的经验，
have and also see the age ranges you can work for. So I know you can work with
并且也了解了你可以胜任的年龄范围。所以我知道你可以和更年轻或
younger or older people. I understood you perfectly. All right, so we also have
更年长的人一起工作。”我完全理解你的意思。好了，那么我们还有
this other really big question. It's always asked when you're asked what are
另一个非常重要的问题。当被问到“你的优点是什么？”时，
your strengths? We have a chance to shine. We can show other people what we've
这总是会被问到。我们有机会大放异彩。我们可以向别人展示我们的实力。
got. What are your strengths, Norma? So you can, but what, but it's going to be
诺玛，你的优点是什么？所以你可以，但是，但是这必须是具体的，对吧？
specific about this, right? Because we can, we can tell someone that we are good
因为我们可以，我们可以告诉别人我们是一个好的倾听者，
listener, but when were you a good listener? And what situation can you be more
但是你什么时候是一个好的倾听者？在什么情况下你可以更具体一些？
specific? This can really help. If you can demonstrate specific, specific
这真的很有帮助。如果你能展示具体的，具体的
examples. And then when you're asked, what is your greatest weakness? You can
例子。然后当你被问到，“你最大的缺点是什么？”你可以
choose a real minor weakness you're actively improving. So this shows that
选择一个你正在积极改进的、真实的、次要的缺点。这样就表明
you're honest. And they say that you should avoid cliche is like, I'm a
你很诚实。他们说你应该避免像“我是一个完美主义者 (wánměi zhǔyì zhě)”这样的陈词滥调 (chéncí làndiào)，
perfectionist, unless you can generally back it up. Are you really a perfectionist?
除非你真的能拿出证据来支持。你真的是一个完美主义者吗？